- [Instructor] Before we get started on installing Mongo,
for those who aren't familiar with Mongo,
here's a quick refresher on what it is.
MongoDB is a database system
that organizes data into collections,
which consist of documents
or objects resembling JSON objects.
These documents contain data structured
in key value pairs or arrays,
allowing for the efficient organization
and retrieval of data.
An example provided is a player's collection
where each player is represented
as a document within this collection.
This structure supports a flexible
and intuitive approach to date management,
catering to a wide range of applications.
So now let's get started on installing Mongo for a server.
In order to be able to use Mongo,
you need to have it installed locally
or use the Atlas cloud-based version.
Feel free to use the cloud-based version if you want.
But for this project, I'll use the local one.
All you have to do is first of all,
look for the Install MongoDB Community page.
So you can search for this on Google,
and once you've found that page,
all you have to do is go
for the operating system that you have
and install it on your system.
So for example, I have macOS,
so I would click here and then follow the instructions.
I'm not going to go through all the instructions
'cause they're well explained here on the website.
So feel free to go ahead and install it on your system.
So you have Windows here.
You have Linux,
and if you want to have a container running Mongo,
you can install it on Docker right here.
Once you have it installed,
and just to make sure that it's working properly
in the background
'cause otherwise, once we start putting the server together,
you're going to have errors running in your console,
what you have to do is go to this webpage, robomongo.org
and installs Studio 3T.
And once you have it installed,
what you can do is literally open it
and open a connection
to localhost port 27017.
This is where Mongo usually runs.
So I can actually click on a connection here,
or you can create a brand new connection by clicking here.
So what you could do is create a new connection
and then add to it.
So let's say, for example,
you didn't have MongoDB already installed.
You can install it manually,
or you can paste the connections here.
But usually, this is the DB server where it's running,
and what you can do, you connect to it,
and if it's connected, and you see the collections here,
you're good to go.